<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Email on VAND3RLINDEN</title>
    <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/email/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Email on VAND3RLINDEN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 17:09:18 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding S/MIME: Enhancing Email Security</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/s-mime-enhancing-email-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 17:09:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/s-mime-enhancing-email-security/</guid>
      <description>This article will help you understand S/MIME and how to request and use it on your devices.
What is S/MIME? In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, the security of sensitive information transmitted via email is critical. One method of safeguarding email communications is through the use of S/MIME (Secure/Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions). S/MIME is a widely adopted protocol that provides end-to-end encryption and digital signatures, ensuring the confidentiality, integrity, and authenticity of email messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get a handle on your SPF record</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/handle-your-spf-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:31:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/handle-your-spf-record/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will share my best practices for getting a handle on your SPF record.
Why it makes sense to have a good SPF procedure in place In a previous blog post, I explained the limitations of SPF, best practices and how it works with DKIM and DMARC. It is useful to have a good SPF procedure to avoid future problems, because if you exceed the DNS lookup limit of 10:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPF, DKIM and DMARC explanation</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/spf-dkim-dmarc-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 11:46:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/spf-dkim-dmarc-explanation/</guid>
      <description>In this post you will learn to understand how the DNS protocols SPF, DKIM and DMARC work together to protect your domain from phishers and spammers.
SPF What is SPF Sender Policy Framework (SPF) is a protocol that aims to reduce spam. SPF can reduce email spoofing and spam by determining if the sender is authorized to send on behalf of the listed sender.
How SPF works Imagine that you have an SPF record that looks like:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
