<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>DNS on VAND3RLINDEN</title>
    <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DNS on VAND3RLINDEN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:30:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhance the visual identity of your email with BIMI</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/bimi-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 23:30:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/bimi-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this post, you will learn what BIMI is, how it works, and the benefits it brings to your domain, including increased trust and brand visibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a time where most first impressions happen online, and emails are usually the first touchpoint. The problem is, inboxes are crowded, and getting someone to notice your message isn’t easy. That’s exactly why BIMI (Brand Indicators for Message Identification) was created. It gives companies a simple way to show who they are and build trust the moment their email lands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MTA-STS Explained: A complete guide to the MTA-STS Policy</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mta-sts-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:22:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mta-sts-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post explains how an MTA-STS policy works and how to implement it on GitHub Pages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MTA-STS (Mail Transfer Agent Strict Transport Security) is a transport security mechanism (TLS enforcement) that protects protects SMTP delivery, it allows a sending (outbound) mail server to enforce the use of TLS by retrieving a secured &lt;code&gt;HTTPS&lt;/code&gt; policy file published by the domain of the receiving (inbound) mail server. This enforcement ensures that connections between mail servers are encrypted and authenticated, preventing attackers from downgrading the connection or intercepting messages through man in the middle attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exchange Online: Configure inbound SMTP DANE with DNSSEC</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/exo-inbound-smtp-dane-dnssec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:13:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/exo-inbound-smtp-dane-dnssec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this post, you will learn how to enable and use SMTP DANE with DNSSEC in Exchange Online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;outbound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; SMTP DANE with DNSSEC in Exchange Online has been enabled since 2022, Microsoft is has rolling out &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inbound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; SMTP DANE with DNSSEC in Exchange Online since late 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a deeper understanding of DNSSEC and DANE, take a look at my earlier &lt;a href=&#34;https://vand3rlinden.com/post/dnssec-dane-explained/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-smtp-dane-with-dnssec-works&#34;&gt;How SMTP DANE with DNSSEC works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SMTP DANE is a transport security mechanism (TLS enforcement) that protects SMTP delivery to a domain by using DNSSEC validated &lt;code&gt;TLSA&lt;/code&gt; records to allow a sending (outbound) mail server to verify the TLS certificate of a receiving (inbound) mail server using &lt;code&gt;TLSA&lt;/code&gt; records published in the DNS of the receiving domain. This helps ensure that TLS connections between mail servers cannot be intercepted or downgraded, protecting against attacks such as TLS downgrade and man-in-the-middle attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the role and benefits of ARC Sealing</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/arc-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 23:37:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/arc-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post explains the role and benefits of ARC sealing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ARC (Authenticated Received Chain) is an email authentication protocol that preserves the authentication results of an email as it travels through multiple intermediaries, such as forwarding services. This allows your recipients to accept the ARC Seal from your relaying or intermediate server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using ARC helps organizations handle the complexities of email authentication, especially when emails are forwarded. ARC involves multiple servers working together based on mutual trust. In this blog post, we will explore the basics of ARC, how it works, and the benefits it provides.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNSSEC and DANE explained</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/dnssec-dane-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 21:51:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/dnssec-dane-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this post, you find out how DNSSEC and DANE cooperate, and learn how to set up DANE TLSA DNS records.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dnssec-dns-security-extensions&#34;&gt;DNSSEC (DNS Security Extensions)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain name system (DNS) is often described as the phone book of the internet for translating friendly domain names into IP addresses. Unfortunately, it also accepts any address given to it. DNSSEC adds a security layer to this phonebook. It uses digital signatures to make sure the information in the phonebook can be trusted and has not been tampered with, to prevent DNS spoofing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get a handle on your SPF record</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/handle-your-spf-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 18:31:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/handle-your-spf-record/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this post, I will share my best practices for getting a handle on your SPF record.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-it-makes-sense-to-have-a-good-spf-procedure-in-place&#34;&gt;Why it makes sense to have a good SPF procedure in place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://vand3rlinden.com/post/spf-dkim-dmarc-explanation/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I explained the limitations of SPF and how it works with DKIM and DMARC. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to have a well-structured SPF procedure to avoid future problems, especially since exceeding the DNS lookup limit of 10 can cause issues, such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPF, DKIM and DMARC explanation</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/spf-dkim-dmarc-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 11:46:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/spf-dkim-dmarc-explanation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this post you will learn to understand how the DNS protocols SPF, DKIM and DMARC work together to protect your domain from phishers and spammers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-deploy-spf-dkim-and-dmarc&#34;&gt;Why deploy SPF, DKIM, and DMARC?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPF, DKIM, and DMARC are critical email authentication protocols that help prevent email spoofing, phishing attacks, and domain impersonation for &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;outbound email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Enabling these protocols together strengthens your domain&amp;rsquo;s email authentication mechanisms, improves security, and builds trust with your recipients by ensuring that email sent from your domain is legitimate and trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
