<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft Defender for Office 365 on VAND3RLINDEN</title>
    <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/microsoft-defender-for-office-365/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft Defender for Office 365 on VAND3RLINDEN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 15:24:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vand3rlinden.com/categories/microsoft-defender-for-office-365/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Defender for Office 365: Anti-spam policies</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mdo-anti-spam-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 15:24:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mdo-anti-spam-policies/</guid>
      <description>All inbound e-mail is automatically protected from spam by Exchange Online Protection (EOP) for Microsoft 365 organizations with mailboxes in Exchange Online. EOP uses anti-spam policies as part of your organization&amp;rsquo;s overall spam defense.
What you can manage with Anti-spam policies Anti-spam policies give you control over inbound and outbound e-mail in Exchange Online. There are three out-of-the-box default policies that you can edit in the Anti-Spam Policy section of the Microsoft Security Portal, where you can also create custom policies (more about this later).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Defender for Office 365: Quarantine policies</title>
      <link>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mdo-quarantine-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 16:33:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vand3rlinden.com/post/mdo-quarantine-policies/</guid>
      <description>Quarantine policies let you control the quarantine on how users can use it. This post will cover the default policies and how to create a custom policy.
What are quarantine policies Back in April 2020, Microsoft made it possible for users to view, release, or delete quarantined messages (expect high confidence phishing). Some organizations were not happy about users having access to their own quarantined items. Quarantine policies give you more control over quarantine for your end users and which quarantined items they can release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
